If this was a VHS tape, it would be
labeled Shan Hardcore Part Two.
>> People would not be getting what they
thought they were getting. [laughter]
>> Here's the Indian guy at his desk
screaming about management hacks.
>> CEO. [laughter]
What I want to talk about is basically
if you're a CEO of a company, if you're
recommending a company right now, which
I think a lot of people listening to
this are, there's a good chance you're
not being hardcore enough. And what I
want to talk about is like six or seven
real anecdotes, stories of what CEOs do,
moves that CEOs do that sound wrong,
sound almost illegal, but they actually
work. The idea being when you're a CEO,
there's no CEO school. There's no CEO
training. There's no nobody there to
manage you. You're the one managing
everybody else and most people don't
even give you like real feedback because
you're kind of their boss. You're in
charge.
>> Is this like famous examples or your
friends?
>> I have a mix of examples you'll know.
Examples I think you won't know but
they're of famous companies and then one
or two from my friends. Okay. So I have
I have one, two, three, four, five. I
have like seven. And whenever you come
up with ideas like this, which you do
all the time, they interest me. But what
also interests me is why do you care?
Why do you care right now?
>> Well, two things. One is in general like
I want to be better at what I do. And so
if I ever hear of somebody else doing
something that I think could be either I
haven't tried or I think like, wow, that
sounds kind of crazy, but I guess I see
how that might work. It's like I kind of
found a new move in a video game and I
like to know that. But the other is we
talk a lot about almost to the point of
it being obnoxious this phrase frame
breaking which is you see the world a
certain way and it seems like there's a
there's a border everything about the
world fits inside that frame and then
you'll hear this story that will just be
outside of the frame. It breaks the
frame. The frame has to expand now
incorporate this new information.
>> And I don't know why I love it. I love
it like dudes love Pokemon cards. I just
want to collect as many of those frame
breaking ideas and stories. And the
reason why is
>> if you've ever heard that story of like
the elephant who as a young age like
they tether him to the stake in the
ground and then he grows and now he's so
powerful he could easily rip out the
stake but he doesn't. There there's many
examples in my life where it feels like
there's the illusion of control that
like I'm limited by something that in in
actuality I'm not limited by at all. The
stories I'm going to tell you are sort
of like elephant in the stake things
where you're like, "Oh, I could I
couldn't possibly do that. Why not? Why
can't you do that?" Before I go into
like kind of the famous stories of
people, you know, doing this, I'll tell
you the guy who I was having breakfast
with that told me a story like this that
got me thinking, got me paying attention
to these. So, I was getting breakfast
recently with this guy, Martin, who will
come on the podcast, Martin Basseri.
Now, Martin was he was like the one that
got away for me. the very first angel
investment I ever wanted to do. 10 plus
years ago, I started making like a
little bit of money. I think I was
making like I don't know 160 grand a
year. Not even that much money. Not
enough money to be, I would say, an
angel investor, but I wanted to be. I
was sitting in San Francisco and I
thought that would be the thing to do. I
should start angel investing. And I had
this kid who was like this 13-year-old
kid who was using one of our products
and he he always used to hang out in the
tech rooms and hang out around tech
things. He emailed me and he said, "Hey,
I'll be your scout." So here I was this
guy who had never made it at angel
investment and now I got a scout and he
said I'm going to send you three
companies a week and you know you don't
have to invest in any of them but it'll
just be great practice for me if you
just give me feedback on those I'd love
to learn.
>> What age are you at this time?
>> I'm probably 24 25 maybe. Yeah.
>> All right.
>> He sends me this email with the first
first company and he goes this guy
Martin Vizier he's in Canada where I
live and already I'm like I'm not trying
to invest in a Canadian company. I want
to invest in Silicon Valley companies.
He's like, what he's doing is really
cool. He's got this company called
Applyboard. And what Applyboard was
doing is very simple. They were letting
international students who, you know, if
you've ever lived internationally, the
dream of most international students is
to come to school in the United States.
>> Yeah.
>> To go to university here. But imagine
just being like a kid in Malaysia with
Malaysian parents. And it's like, great,
why don't you apply to um whatever UC
Davis? And they're like, what what is UC
Dav where is that school? How do I
apply? How do I fill out this form? like
it's a very like there's a huge gap
between where you are and where you're
trying to go and you need a bridge and
apply board became that bridge. They
basically made it very easy for foreign
students to apply to US universities and
what they did they realized it was very
smart
>> was that US universities absolutely rip
off foreign international students.
There's a reason they love international
students is because they charge them
three times the price to go to school
and this to the same school get the same
education. So if you're a state school,
you'll obviously charge less for instate
tuition, out of state tuition. And then
there's a third tier called
international tuition. It's three times
higher.
>> And so he went to the schools and he got
the schools to say, "Yeah, I'll pay you
five grand or 10 grand per student that
we admit like as a as an affiliate fee,
as a bounty."
>> So this is like an incredible and the
international is dying to go there. So
it's not the hardest sell in the world.
They just needed a bridge. So I hear
this, I'm like, "Dude, this 13-year-old
might have actually sent me a good
company." And I'm like, "Okay."
>> The guy was 13.
>> The scout was 13.
>> Wow. [laughter]
>> Okay.
>> And so he I'm like, "Dude, I think I'm
going to do this deal." And so he he
comes out. I meet him in San Francisco
and I agree on the spot. I'm going to
invest 25 grand into this company. And I
said it very confidently to him,
>> which is a huge amount of money, by the
way.
>> Your annual savings in San Francisco on
$170,000 was $20,000.
>> Yeah, exactly. I was basically putting
all of my like post tax disposal income
into this one random Canadian startup.
Well, guess what? A day later, your boys
got cold feet. I'm like, "Oh man, that
was a lot. I shouldn't have said that. I
felt stupid coming down. I was like, do
I go back to him and say 5 grand, 10
grand? That felt stupid." And you know
what I did? I didn't back out, but I
just didn't say anything. And like I
didn't follow up and he didn't really
follow up. And some time went by and
then I got unavailable. And then
anyways, I missed out on this deal.
Applyboard today I think it does over
like a billion dollars a year in revenue
or something crazy. It's like a
multi-billion dollar company. It's in
it's insane. I don't know the exact
numbers but I know it's multi-billion
dollar company. So huge miss for me on
that. That's for the very first possible
angel investment.
>> What was his valuation back then?
>> Oh dude it must have been like I don't
know $10 million or something. Yeah.
Five six. I would have been the first
investor in like first Silicon Valley
investor in it.
>> Yeah. There was it would have been
amazing. So last week I'm having
breakfast with him and I've now invested
in his new company, Passage, which is
doing some amazing things. But uh I'm
saying like, "Dude, how's it?" I was
like, "How is it like how do you
operate?" I was like, "Tell me like
we're having breakfast right now. You're
going to go to the office. What do you
do?" And he was he was like, "I work
pretty hard." And he's like I was like,
"Okay, what does that mean?" And so he's
telling me his work schedule. The guy
basically like, "I drop off my kids, you
know, 8 a.m. I'm in the office at 8:30
and I'm there from 8:30 to, you know,
midnight every night. And I'm like,
"Midnight? Jesus Christ." I was like,
"Are you the only one there?" He goes,
"I used to be, but not anymore." I was
like, "Well, what do you what do you
mean?" Like, "How'd you get people to
start staying so late to work like extra
like that? Like, what'd you do to
inspire them, motivate them?" He goes,
"Ooption drop." I [laughter] said,
"What?" And and he's like, "Ooption
drop." I said, "What's an option drop?"
He goes, "At any time in my company, if
anybody does something awesome, I just
say option drop. 50,000 options." I just
give them share options at the company
on the spot. Like if somebody has a
great idea, they go above and beyond for
a customer. They solve a problem in the
meeting right there. Option drop.
>> It's like Dana White giving out a bonus.
>> What I'll do, he say it's a bonus, but
stocking the company on the fly. And he
goes and and then at night he goes if
I'm there 10 p.m. and if there's like
let's say 12 people there I'll just say
everybody here option drop 20,000
options all of you. He's like I don't do
it every night but I'll do it once every
you know 50 days. And guess what? It got
people to start doing the things that I
cared about. They know if I solve a big
problem, if I unlock some new growth, if
I solve a customer's problem, if I'm
working really hard, that's how I get
more options. Option drop. And I was And
so I'm sitting there and I'm like
laughing. So, I'm laughing at him first
because I'm like, that's just hilarious.
Just the phrase and the way he said it,
I just was cracking me up. And I was
like, well, of course, of course that
would work. Of course, that would
reinforce behaviors rather than saying,
well, I put our company values on the
wall once 6 years ago. I sure hope
they're doing it. You know what I mean?
Like obviously a in the- moment
incentive, positive reinforcement for a
behavior. the more specific, the more
concrete, and the more immediate a
reward, the more more of that behavior
you're going to get. That's kind of
basic behavioral science. So, I was
like, "Okay, I guess that does work."
And I was like, "Is that legal? Could
you?" I was like, "I don't know. I just
can't feel like you can't just throw
around options like that." He's like,
"Why not?"
>> Yeah, you could.
>> He's like, "I just send a message to my
assistant, option drop these people,
this amount, and then it gets papered.
That's it."
>> Well, and and it's an option, meaning
they still have to buy it, right? So,
it's not like it's free money.
>> Um, yeah. Like this has a strike price.
Yeah. So you can you can exercise the
option if you if you so choose.
>> But there's that exercise window. You
don't have to buy it right away. You can
you know you can wait if you want. So
okay, option drop was the first one of I
was like, oh obviously a way to um
incentivize the types of behaviors that
you want right there on the spot using
your company's share options. Can I give
you the next one?
>> Keep going. This is exciting.
>> Any any you want to rate these? Maybe
give me a you know give me a you have a
very simple let's do gladiator thumbs
down lukewarm thumbs up or double thumbs
up. That's your options.
>> Um not a double thumbs up. So just one
one thumb up.
>> Okay. [laughter]
>> Yeah, that's that's very effective.
Good. Not that like extreme.
>> Do you do it?
>> I don't do options but because Yeah.
Like I just give money.
>> Okay. Do you do that on the spot?
>> No.
>> Okay. But I'm also not the CEO and I'm
also not extreme. [laughter]
>> Like, you know what I mean? Like, I'm
not playing that game.
>> What? The game of trying to win? What do
you mean? Of course you are.
>> Not Not at the price of being there at
midnight. No, I'm more of a
>> It doesn't It doesn't have to be
midnight, right? Like that. That's one.
You just decide of the things I care
about. Do I on the fly reward the
behaviors I want?
>> We do it via having a gong in the
office. And when someone does something
awesome, we smack a gong. So, [laughter]
>> auditory.
Well, well, it's just like cuz everyone
stares at it and you're like, we're
going to like celebrate what is
happening right now. But no, I don't
give up money.
>> Okay, here's the next one.
>> Hey everyone, really quick. If you're
enjoying this episode on CEO stuff, so
delegating, having hard conversations
with your team, hiring, then I've got
something for you. So, the team at
HubSpot, they actually went and put
together a bunch of best practices that
Sean and I use in our own companies, and
they put it together in something that's
really easy to read and understand. And
so if you want to just save yourself 10
years of headache and heartache, then
you should check it out. I wish we had
this a long time ago. It would have
helped me a lot. But there should be a
QR code on your screen that you can scan
or a link in the description. So check
it out. It's totally free and totally
awesome.
Open AAI, the makers of chat GPT, they
are trying to fight friction. So in
every company, there's just a whole
bunch of Especially as you
grow, and when you're like them, you
grow very fast. There's always just
things that are just drag in
bureaucratic drag in the company.
Policies, procedures,
you know, potholes, things that just
start to trip you up as you're working
in the company. Just try to do good
work. So, they created what they call
the friction removal service. It's sort
of like a Doge idea inside the company,
but it's actually very simple, which is
there's an email inbox called friction
openai.com
>> and you could just email friction with
any thing that's causing that's causing
you to not get your job done. So, like,
is there something slowing you down? Is
there something that's missing? Is there
something that's a problem? Anything
that's there? And there's a person
assigned to the company whose job is to
triage everything that comes in there.
And if there's something that seems
like, oh, that's actually a pretty like
legitimate source of friction, we should
get we should eliminate that. That's
going to help our people move faster and
then they go and they move they they
remove that friction. And it creates a
culture of saying like, look,
>> we are going to actively fight the bloat
that comes in companies that grow really
big and grow really fast
>> by having a janitorial crew for a
bureaucracy. I was like, "Oh, I kind of
love that idea." So,
>> yeah, that's brilliant.
>> Give me a score.
>> Two. Just two. Am I allowed to do two?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Double thumbs up. All right.
>> What a a Caesar would never do that, but
that's okay.
>> Yeah.
It's sort of it's sort of giving like
Chuck-E-Cheese instead of Gladiator.
[laughter]
>> Uh, no. Two, because that is like less
heroic and more systematic. Yeah, I'm on
totally on board with that.
>> All right. Next one is one bit
communication. So, do you remember this
app, Yo, from back in the day?
>> Yeah. Hilarious. All the rage when you
and I were 26 years old. So people, you
don't you you'll only know if you know,
which is back in the day in San
Francisco, this app became the rage for
like I want to say 30 days.
>> Yeah. If there was like a one hit wonder
like song list for Silicon Valley, that
would be Chumba Womba.
>> I get knocked down by Chumba Womba and
then Yo are both on that list.
>> Describe what Yo did.
>> I think it was just an app where your
friends downloaded and you clicked one
button and it said yo to the other
person. I think that's it. And then if
they clicked the button it would say yo
>> yo right back. All you could say is yo
to each other. And so it seemed like the
stupidest thing in the world. It was
going viral for being almost so silly.
And then Andre and Horowitz wrote a big
check into them. And we were like what?
You know one of the smartest investors
invested in yo are you kidding me? It
was like straight out of the TV show
Silicon Valley. In fact, I think they
they mocked this by with the bro app in
the in the show whereas you said bro to
each other. But I was like why? And Mark
Andre wrote this blog post called one
bit communication and he talked about
how like um there are many forms of
communication, right? You can write
letters, you can write text messages
which haveund whatever 40 or 160
character limit. You had beepers back in
the day and a beeper was just a way to
get your attention and you kind of had
to know if I'm beeping you with this
code that what that code means. And he
goes, "The smallest form of
communication would be a one bit
communication, just a single bit back
and forth, yo, but yo can mean a lot."
And he wrote this like very like this
like thesis on yo. And I just remember
reading it and being like honestly kind
of have convinced about this, you know,
like a smart guy could really sell you
anything. And he did. He sold me that.
Well, I've learned that there's a couple
CEOs who use one bit communication. So
here's the first one. Seammens. The
seaman CEO came out and he said, "Yeah,
I have a very specific management
system. My management system is this.
You email me anything you want to talk
to me about and I will respond with okay
or no." That's it. I'm just going to say
okay or no to your email. And if it
requires more than that, then um you're
going to come talk to me. And when do
you come talk to me? We don't have
weekly recurring like calendar meetings.
We don't have like scheduling. If you
need me, you'd come talk to me right
now. And that's it. That's how I unblock
everybody in the company. and I will not
be the bottleneck. I'm simply going to
give you permission rejection or if
there needs to be more detail, you'll
find out that you need to come talk to
me right now and we'll we'll discuss
more and then you'll get the okay or no
after more detail has been revealed.
>> Yeah, this guy's having like a moment
right now. I think I saw a few articles
about him. What happened with him?
>> Well, he's he's like a theoretical
physics uh background CEO, but he's a
CEO and so they always kind of if you
come from a a non-traditional background
today and cool
>> and he goes I love this quote. He goes,
they go, "So, you don't have any
recurring meetings with your direct
reports like to to sit and just catch up
and discuss?" And he goes, "I don't
entertain people and they don't need to
entertain me." [laughter]
Which is if you think about like if you
ever been in a company, a lot of like
the meetings you have are really
theater, right? It's it's progress
theater. Like I would like to put on a
little play for you of how good I'm
doing and then you you sit in the back
and you you give me a little, you know,
theater clap back to me and I feel good
and then I go on my way and we've both
just kind of wasted an hour of each
other's time. And it's not the work
isn't getting done there. That's just
basically like you don't trust me enough
to just do the thing and I don't trust
you enough to know that I can just show
you the work and that's that's enough
for you to understand my my value. So
we'll tap dance for each other.
>> Is he German? I see.
>> It's a very German behavior.
>> Yeah, he's German. I had to look him up
because I I think Simmons is a German
company. This guy's great. Is this going
to be like the new Snowflake CEO?
>> Maybe. Maybe. Early signs. My scouts, my
scouts are paying attention to this.
>> We have to get on this train early. Uh,
two. [laughter]
>> All right. Related the Jeff B
escalation. So, this is Bezos. So, Bezos
famously would read any customer email.
You know, his his email was out there so
customers could email him and he would
just be like a router. He would route
the email to the team if there was a
problem and it would only have one bit
in it. One bit communication, just a
question mark, which has got to be like
the most annoying thing that any CEO
could do. But he trained the team that
the question mark has a very specific
meaning. And the if he sends you the
question mark, it means, is this true?
Why is this happening? And what are we
going to do about it? all encoded into a
one question mark thing allowing him to
actually like triage his email way
faster than having to like take each
thing find a good time to bring it up
when can I bring this up with you know
then I delay and then I bring it up and
then we're going to have to have this
long conversation just one question mark
and that's what he would do and his take
was this he would say at the beginning a
lot of the teams would say no no that's
just you know that's just one loud angry
customer or something like that look the
data shows that we're 98% %, you know,
success rate. And his take was, look,
we're a very datadriven company, but
these customer anecdotes matter and they
matter a lot. And I want you to
investigate these because I'm not saying
when I send you this customer email, I'm
not saying drop what you're doing and go
satisfy Joanne in Witchah, this prime
customer. You know, you don't need to
solve her problem. What I'm saying is
Amazon is a machine. The machine might
be broken. And this anecdote is a little
bit of a signal. It's a squeak in the
machine that I'd like you to investigate
to see why this would happen cuz that's
not how the machine is designed to work.
>> Yeah, I tend to think those stories are
more important than than traditional
data.
>> And what he said was he goes, "Look,
you're not wrong. That maybe 98% is
happening the way you want. What I'm
telling you is that the anecdotes
typically show you that your metric is
incomplete, that it's not capturing some
part of the customer's experience that
actually matters. And both the metric is
right and the customer is right. the
metric is just incomplete because it's
not capturing this part of the
customer's experience. I was like, "Oh,
I kind of like that. That's a very that
would have been a very satisfying
explanation for what would have
otherwise been an absolutely infuriating
thing of just getting this one question
mark from your CEO forwarding a random
customer complaint to you as the head of
whatever some part of the business."
>> And I think a question mark from you or
I would come off incredibly douchy.
There's something about Jeff that seems
a little bit more polite and respectful.
And so I don't take it as a douchy
thing. Originally, when I heard question
mark, I was like, that's that's pretty
disrespectful. But I don't view him as a
disrespectful guy. When I if you see me
send a question mark, assume it's
disrespect.
>> It is disrespect. [laughter]
>> Yeah.
>> It's because they don't have a backhand
slap emoji. [laughter]
>> Yeah. I can't punch you through a
screen. All right. What's the next one?
>> All right. Next one comes from Peter
Teal. Okay. So Peter Teal famously at
when he was the CEO of PayPal, he had
this thing that I really loved which he
goes, "We are going to be a single
tasking company. You are not going to be
a multitasker." Which is great because
PayPal was full of some of the biggest
brains in the world, right? Max Levchin,
Elon Musk, Reed Hoffman, the creators of
YouTube, the creators of Yelp, the
creator obviously like a bunch of big
brains in that room. You would think if
anybody could multitask, it'd be those
people. Well, no. Peter's take was this.
Everybody has one big problem that
you're trying to solve at any given
time. Like you might be fighting fraud
from the Ukraine right now and you might
be trying to optimize virality of the
PayPal button on eBay and this other guy
might be trying to, you know, um, lower
our, you know, processing fees with the
banks, right? So everybody's assigned
one problem and his thing was this. They
go, well, you know, how do you get
people to actually do that? Right?
Because sounds good in theory, right?
Focus is always a word everybody nods
and agrees on, but we're all pretty bad
at focus. So how did you get your teams
to actually do it? And Peter Thiel's
answer was, "Oh, if if they tried to
talk to me about anything besides their
problem, I would just simply walk out of
the room." [laughter] And the non-verbal
communication was pretty clear how I
felt. [laughter]
And and people were like, "Did he really
do that?" And Keith, you know, Keith Rey
was like, "Yeah, he would literally do
that. He would if you tried to bring up
anything else besides your problem, he
would just turn around and he would just
walk away." And then you got the signal
of how important that was. And if you
wanted to be valued by the CEO, you
would stay on task of your problem.
[laughter]
>> He would just do like the autistic
clump. Just you your feet just clmping
away at the [laughter] door.
>> Did you think he was wearing shoes? No
chance that he was wearing shoes in that
office. So,
>> no, dude. He's a loafer guy. You cuz
he's the type of guy where you just hear
clamping around. I can tell.
>> Focus is convex. Unfortunately, I'm too
stupid exactly what that means, but it
sounds very provocative and I've used it
three times since. Um, the good news is
nobody else I work with knows what it
means either. [laughter]
>> I don't know what this has to do with
focus. That's what convex looks like.
>> Explain a little bit. He goes,
>> "If you are 80% focused on a task, that
will only be half as good as if you were
90%." Meaning the jump from 80% focused
to 90% focus will double your impact.
And so you really want this the last
mile of focus, the last level of
ruthlessness about your focus will will
double, you know, you'll get one or two
more doubles in the output. Um, which
kind of makes sense. Like if you look at
any field, right? If you're the 80th
percentile swimmer, nobody knows your
name and you work at a tire company. If
you're the 90th percent swimmer, you
know, people in your county might know
your name, but you still you manage the
tire company. If you're the 99th
percentile swimmer, you might, you know,
be able to swim professionally, but if
you're the 99.99999, right? Like the
final, it's that last leg, you're
Michael Phelps and, you know, you get
all the gold medals and the millions of
dollars and so on. And it's basically
like your use of focus that the last
mile of it, the last level of obsession
is what gets you like a disproportionate
amount of the rewards.
>> So, what's point number um three or are
we on four on Sean's hardcore
>> [laughter]
>> If this was a VHS tape, it would be
labeled Shan Hardcore Part Two.
[laughter]
>> People would not be getting what they
thought they were getting.
>> Indian guy at his desk screaming about
management hacks.
>> CEO. [laughter]
Put the O and CEO. Uh, all right. Here's
what we got. What's left? I got I did
one, two, three, four, five. I got five.
I got three left. All right. Jack Welch,
CEO of of GE, when you ran when you run
a big company, it's very easy for, you
know, all your children are sort of not
equal. They're not loved equally, all
the different business divisions. And GE
was in very a bunch of different
business divisions. And he had two
simple rules when he was running GE. One
was every division, you need to be
number one or number two in your market.
Otherwise, you have one year to fix it,
sell it, or close it. That's it. we will
trim the business divisions unless you
can be number one or number two which is
an incredible forcing function because
it's a sort of Darwinian pressure to
survive and the other Darwinian pressure
he applied was every year Jack Welch
would fire the bottom 10% performers in
the company every year and so a a
continuous culling of the herd which
sounds I mean I'm sure people interpret
that different way some people will
think he's an for that when I
first heard it I was like oh that's that
doesn't sound that hardcore but then you
go try do it. Go try to do that every
year. It is incredibly difficult. Or go
look at your own track record. How much
low performance have you tolerated
because you don't fire people until push
really comes to shove. I think Jack
Welch is I think he's controversial. We
actually should do a deep dive one day
on him because people say that he was a
horrible CEO because if you look at like
GE, it was kind of became this like
amalgamation of like a bunch of like
nonsense and it like owned a bunch of
stuff that ended up not working out. But
I don't know enough about Jack Walsh to
know if that was his doing or what
happened. But but I know that he was
well loved as a leader. But at the same
time, I hear smart people say the exact
opposite about firing. Like Jensen from
Nvidia, he was like he was like, "I'm
going to smother you in greatness. I'm
not going to fire you." Like it's so
funny how great people, assuming they
both are great, have different opinions
on firing as I mean as well as
everything else. Like total opposite,
right?
>> Yeah. Yeah. And you you will find that
for for every single one of these, you
will find people who are very successful
doing the polar opposite, which is not
meant to say that this is the way to be
great. It's just meant to say, damn, I
thought these stories were pretty
hardcore, huh? That's really kind of all
we're saying. And that there are it kind
of pushes the boundaries of your
thinking of what is acceptable,
tolerable, and potentially um effective.
You know, I think firing your low
performers is a pretty, I would say,
logical thing to do. Meaning,
>> yeah,
>> I could see why that works. [laughter]
I could definitely see why that works.
And I'm I'm in support of that one. But
yeah, I think others, you know, like
like I think Jensen said when he made
that point, he was like, "Yeah, I don't
fire them, but I turn up the intensity
so much that you either become great or
quit, right?" which is more of a sink or
swim version of like, yeah, they quit
instead of getting fired. But either
way, you weed out the low performers one
way or another. So, last two. Um, all
right, I'm going to skip this last one.
I'll tell you, I don't even really like
it. The Ford CEO, this guy comes in,
this guy Allen becomes the Ford CEO.
They had just lost 17 billion last year,
and he came in and they did like the
business review where they go through
all the different business like projects
and how they're on track or off track.
And it was like color coded like green
is on track, yellow is at risk and red
is off track and everything was green.
And he's like guys we lost 17 billion
last year. How was everything green? And
he realized they had like a culture
where you know people were sort of
afraid to admit failure. And so he's
like you can't be afraid. You you have
to be honest. And so the next week they
were all green again except for one was
red. And he stood up and started
clapping and uh changed the uh the
culture around failure. And I was like
it sounds a little bit like a Disney
movie to me.
Cool running
>> Yeah. [laughter] So, I think we're going
to think we're going to thumbs down
Allan together here.
>> Nice try, Alan. Consider me uninspired.
Um,
>> all right. The last one comes from Jimmy
aka Mr. Beast, which was I think you
were there when he described his cloning
strategy, which we were like, "So, dude,
how do you train your employees? They're
all really young. Seems like they're all
new. You're growing so fast. Like, do
you have like I'm just curious like you
don't you know, you never went to
college or business school or anything
like that. like what what do you do for
your like kind of management? And he's
like, "Oh, I just do cloning." And we're
like, "That sounds illegal. What does
that mean?" And he's like, "Well, if I
hire you in one of like kind of the key
roles, you just follow me everywhere.
Like you literally shadow me every
single place I go." And I think the guy
who initially was doing it was like
sleeping at the same house that he was
in. Like it was like that that hardcore.
Like from morning to night, like the guy
I remember one guy he hired, he he was
also Jimmy's alarm clock. like he would
go wake him up and from the moment Jimmy
woke up they were together till the
moment Jimmy signed off to go to sleep
and he would do that for 6 months and
he's like by the end of 6 months you
know exactly how I think cuz you've been
with me every everywhere you know you
saw every decision I made so essentially
you're like a proxy for me like I can
now be in two places at once because you
know exactly what would Jimmy do in this
situation and yeah cloning works great
and I remember there was like a room
full of CEOs like multi-billion dollar
CEOs as he was telling us this who were
like I think that's awesome in illegal
like [laughter] what
these people don't like get weekends.
He's like, "No, you come here to you
come here to win." I don't know if he
still does it, but in the early days of
his thing, I thought that was pretty
pretty awesome.
>> How is that going? Like it's it's
interesting to hear about extreme people
and how it ends up um like if they if
they soften it when they have kids and
stuff. It appears as though Elon is not
a guy who has softened at all as the
company has gotten bigger and has he has
more had more kids. I wonder if that's
happened with Jimmy and what's it
called? Beast Enterprise or I don't know
what it's called. Beast Beast
Industries.
>> Yeah, I think both. Right. I think he
matured, right? When we met him, he's
probably only like 25 or 24 years old or
something like that, right? So like you
>> matured like hugely from year over year.
>> Yeah, you're going to mature and his
rate of learning like he's, you know,
pretty obsessive about learning from
smart people and so he his the slope of
his line is pretty crazy, right? So, I'm
sure a lot has changed. At the same
time, if something's working and that's
your edge, you got to be pretty careful.
You don't just dull out all your edges.
And so, yeah, he does have a CEO now.
Beast Industries. I'm sure they have
more people and they're less like kind
of business malpractice as you know, you
do in the early days when you're kind of
rough and tumble and figure things out.
But, yeah, dude. I think they still go
pretty hard and try to win. And I think
that, you know, I think a lot of the
fundamentals are probably still there of
the stuff that works, right?
like anything, the stuff that's working
tends to survive and the stuff that's
ineffective tends to get pruned out over
time.
>> I am not compared to these guys, I we're
not even in the same ballpark in terms
of being like hardcore. Um I don't know
where you are, but I know that when I
hear this, I'm like, uh it sounds like a
lot of work. I'm not into that. I don't
I don't want the same outcomes. And I
had a story for you today that is the
exact opposite of hardcore. I didn't
mean for this story to be a matter of
hardcore or not. More so a matter of
there's money everywhere.
>> Can I give you an anecdote that like
supports what you're saying about the
the other side of the the coin here?
David Prell, friend of the pod, had
Kevin Kelly on the podcast. And Kevin
Kelly is this guy who I I really like
and admire. He had a really eclectic
career. He like started Wired magazine
and he wrote A Thousand True Fans, which
really shaped kind of my thinking. Was
he like a was he I know he's like a
thinker and a writer, but was he a
successful business person, too?
>> Yeah, I think he's done well like he's I
he's done done very well compared to
normal standards, but like you know, not
not like some crazy whatever billionaire
type, but I don't think that was ever
his goal, but he's just done a bunch of
really interesting projects and his
projects very successful. He asked him a
great question about this. He he asked
him something like like what's been the
cost of being Kevin Kelly? like what
have you given up to be Kevin Kelly the
way you the way you have? And Kevin's
like, you know, that's a great question.
To have this life I have, I had to give
up on greatness.
>> And he goes, what do you mean? And he
goes, well, I think the cost of
greatness is some level of being
extreme.
And I just never wanted to be extreme. I
didn't want the cost of extreme. And so
he's like, I surrendered to the path of
I'm not going to be as great as I
possibly could be had I been obsessively
focused on one thing. Had I been more
extreme, had I given up certain parts of
my personal life. And he goes, I give
you I'll give you a very specific
definition of greatness. And he goes,
let's just for lack of a better word,
because I could say greatness and it
means two different things in our heads.
He goes, let's say greatness is being
remembered by people other than your
family more than one generation from
now.
And he goes, "I don't think I will be
remembered for anything more than one or
two generations from now from anyone
outside of my own family." And he goes,
"To be to be able to be," he goes, "Like
a gadfly where I just kind of float from
thing to thing and I I get to dabble and
explore and like kind of see different
projects and bring them to life in
little ways, but I don't own any of
them. Not any of them became the biggest
thing in the world." To be the Gadfly, I
had to surrender and and give up on the
path of greatness. And I'm I'm I'm
perfectly happy with that. And I thought
it was just a very I never really heard
anyone
say it that way. Like I kind of
respected his thinking on two levels.
One, I don't think people ever define
the words what they mean. I just like
that he started by being like, I can't
give you this answer if I don't define
what this word means to me.
>> Was it grandchildren or
great-grandchildren?
>> So, let's just say grandchildren. Yeah.
>> Okay. That's actually interesting. I've
always I've had a similar definition of
greatness, but it's always been way
longer where it's been like 120 or 150
years, which I guess would be a couple
more add a few more generations to that.
But that's actually an interesting way
to define it.
>> Yeah. Like you could I mean I don't know
who you would consider to be great, but
like whether it's you know Steve Jobs on
the business side, right? Like you could
go into like you know Gandhi and Nelson
Mandela and like people who did great in
in terms of their civic actions or
people like Houdini people who are great
artists and great creators that way
right like there's all these kind of
people who are great if you look at them
very few of them live very chill
balanced lifestyles right like there
ain't normal people on the top of uh uh
Mount Everest like you're not going to
find well balanced people I actually
think about that all the time because I
love history and I'll see street names
and it's clearly named after someone and
I'll go and research who that person is.
Like for example, Fort Green is named
after Nathaniel Green. Fort Green is a
neighborhood in Brooklyn. It's a it's a
park and it's named after Nathaniel
Green who was a general in the American
Revolution. And he's he was a big shot
in the American Revolution, one of the
key generals. And it's like, does
remembered mean his name is named after
a park in which no one even knows that
Fort Green was Nathaniel Green? And I'm
like, this guy was one of the key top 20
people in the American Revolution, which
is one of the most consequential
consequential revolutions of all time.
And I don't even know him. Um, and and
when you think about it, over the last
500 to a,000 years, there of the
billions and billions of billions of
people who have ever existed, the ones
who do, who we remember, more often than
not, it has nothing to do with money.
For example, if you and I do the best
that we will ever do when it comes to
business, the likelihood that we will be
within like maybe there's a world where
we'll crack the top 5,000 or top 10,000
living Americans in terms of wealth.
Maybe that would be obviously 0.00001%
of like that, right? And yet even that
is not going to get you remembered for
500 years. You can't name who the 80th
richest person was in the 19
>> 1930s. 50 years.
>> Yeah. Yeah. You can't. So that's like so
so therefore
>> who's that person today? You don't know
now.
>> Yeah. You don't know. And so and then
you're like, okay, so I won't know that.
Okay. So money can't really be it.
>> And then it's like, okay, what about
business? It's like well there's a some
companies that have lasted that long but
like it's basically when you really
think about it it's like humanitarians a
handful of amazing like leaders or
politicians which would also include
like the Mother Teresa's of the world
like someone who did something really
special and then it's like inventors
like it it's like
invented something
>> or an artist occas like occasionally an
artist
>> and I'm like so when I think about that
I'm like well the odds if I define
greatness as me being remembered for
like let's say 150 or 200 years. I'm
like a I'm doing it wrong and b the odds
are so low and then I was like therefore
maybe I just shouldn't care.
>> Like I like I I felt like years working
through this.
>> Can I tell you where I landed with that
same idea being remembered or legacy
type stuff never really appealed. I
think I was pretty quick to shed that
one. In fact, there's a great Hormosi
once said something [laughter] I really
loved. He was like, "You know, the queen
died six months ago and guess what? She
was the queen. And I bet you haven't
thought about her since she died.
[laughter] I was like, "Oh, that's so
true. That's the queen, you know, that's
the queen of England after a hundred
years, you know, dying." And so I never
really cared about the legacy stuff so
much, but I wanted to achieve greatness.
And when I thought about achieving
greatness, it was some version of
success or, you know, building something
that mattered in the world or, you know,
like the the number one of something,
being the number one of something. And
what I've realized is that achieving
greatness was sort of like not not for
me. It would be a fool's errand for me.
It's not what I'm wired to do. It's not
what I would enjoy to do. It's it comes
at a cost that I would not be willing to
pay once I knew the cost. But there's a
big difference between achieving
something great and being great. I know
a lot of people who are great. Our buddy
Ramon is great. He's a great friend.
He's a great dad. He's a great guy. And
he's a great hang. And you know what I
mean? He he he is good at being great.
You you'd mentioned Ben Wilson. Ben
Wilson right now is being great in
handling such a difficult circumstance
with absolute, you know, class and
courage. And there's just being great.
My trainer is a guy. He's just great.
He's he's a great guy. He's a great
uncle to my kids. He's a great um you
know, great trainer. He cares about
people, you know, he's so fun to be
around. He's he's always in a great
mood. He's that's called being great.
And so I realized like being great, the
active tense, the day-to-day thing,
that's the thing to chase because you
could do it right now. And in the
moment, how you're showing up, you could
be great right now. And you could also
fall out of being great if you lose
track of that. And you should get right
back on the horse, try to be great
again. And I think that was the where I
landed. I was like, "Okay, I think I
that resonates for me. Feel I feel
comfortable with that." And it's a it's
a far more holistic sense. It's you
could be great when you're exercising
and you're in the last three reps of the
set and you have to decide if you're
going to put the reps if put the weight
down or if you're going to push yourself
and try to really like see what you're
made of. That's a moment of being great.
You know, you could just be courteous
and kind to somebody. That's a moment of
being great. You know, like sometimes
I'm with I'm at the park and there's
other kids and they're kind of like, you
know, talking to me and I'm kind of just
like, I don't know why this
four-year-old is talking to me. And
sometimes I brush them off and I just
want to be on my phone. I don't really
want to talk to this stranger kid about
like, you know, this caterpillar that he
found. And sometimes I indulge them and
I'm like, "No, I I, you know, I'll say
something to them that's plays back into
them because that's how I would want
someone to treat my kid." It's a moment
where I get to choose if I'm going to be
great or if I'm not going to be great.
And I'm not always I'm not always the
best at that, but increasing that hit
rate is the goal. And that's one I can
kind of get behind.
>> What's the phrase again? Say this again.
I think this is good. Instead of
building something great, be great.
>> Yeah. Don't try to achieve greatness.
Like just be great right now. Like just
being great.
>> Did you see the guy who go went viral?
um this week on Twitter where he was
like saying like someone was talking
about like hard work and he was like I
think you should work hard but but
there's a there's this a age between
like 3 years old and 13year-old where
your kids don't dislike you yet and
they're willing to spend time with you
know past 13 that doesn't happen and
they're out of diapers so they're a
little bit easier and they start having
opinions and then they can think and for
a lot of men who are ambitious people
what they notice is that their ambition
goes away or dials down during in this
period because they love being around
their kids. And it doesn't happen to
everyone, but a lot of men do. And what
I've noticed is that the people who are
fearful of this, I just want to let you
know that it tends to come back.
Ambition does come back. And the reason
why this went viral is because I'm
experiencing this and I think maybe you
are and a lot of our um our folks
listening are. But like there is this
moment where you start like experiencing
these things with your kids when they
start having opinions and they still
like hanging out with you and you're
like I don't know if I care about the
same things like ambition or these other
things where I dedicated my life to
them. I guess I'm not willing to pay
that price. And frankly I find it to be
kind of a pain in the ass because you're
like life was so much simpler. just
climb the ladder, make money, you know?
It's like f chicks and get money. Like,
[laughter] like it's so much simpler
that way. And then you have kids and
you're like, "Shit, everything I thought
to be true, it's not true right now."
>> And the the poster was like, "But it
becomes true again later on." Like you,
it does come back. But I remember
reading that last weekend and it really
hits hit with me because when you're
talking about these like guys who are
hardcore, I'm like, I don't want I'm not
staying till midnight right now.
>> Yeah. No, [laughter]
my chair has lumbar support.
>> I don't think I'm going to be here till
midnight. [laughter]
>> That that ain't happening.
>> No option drops for us. [laughter]
>> Yeah,
>> dude. I gave him a great idea at the
breakfast and he option dropped me. I
was like, "Yes." [laughter]
Immediately like hook, line, and sinker.
I was like, "Wow, how do I get that
again?" That was a really [laughter]
I like that reward.
Um, I was going to bring up another
story, but I'm not going to anymore. I
think that was perfect. [laughter]
>> Yeah, that'd be a little too hardcore
for us, too. But we're going to chill
out at 55 minutes and not go to the 60.
[laughter]
>> No, I think this has a good bow tie to
it. Or bow tie a good, you know,
[clears throat] whatever that phrase is
about
presents and [laughter] uh rapid
It's all done. I don't know. All right,
that's it. That's a pod.